♪♪～
A symphony of disintegration resounds
The falling rain has the exact timbre of tears
Realize
Those eyes are for recognizing each other with
Those voices are for
conveying our feelings with
Those hands are for joining
hands with our loved ones
All you living beings who can hear this song
The truth lies within your heart
And even when you're traveling a stormy sea
It will give you a strength
That will never flinch
Revolution
（生徒）おい。
議事堂も　のみ込まれたぞ。
- Hey, it even swallowed up the Diet Building!
- It's practically right in our faces now!
すぐ目の前じゃねえか。
（生徒）どうするの？→
What should we do?
In another week, this place will be...
あと１週間もすれば
ここも…。
What are you doing?
≪（集）何をしている？
（生徒）会長…。
Mr. President!
（集）君たちが
監視を怠ったせいで→
What if you let the enemy take us by surprise
because you took your minds
off your observation duties?
敵の奇襲を許したら→
そのとき出た犠牲に
責任が取れるのか？
Would you be able to take
responsibility for the casualties?
何だ　それ…。
What's his problem?
親衛隊。　彼らを懲罰房に。
（難波）はい。
Secret Service, take them
to the disciplinary cell.
Yes, Sir.
な…。
（生徒）マジかよ！
Seriously?!
Screw you! Where do you get off...
ふざけんなよ！
好き勝手なこと言いやがって！
うっ…。
うあ…。　うあぁぁ！
僕には　こいつを
どうすることだって　できるんだぞ。
I can do whatever I want with this, you know!
それが嫌なら　僕に従え！！
If you don't like the sound of that, then obey me!
（谷尋）まだ寝ないのか？
寝てられないよ。
Not in bed yet?
I can't sleep at a time like this.
There's only a week until the Exodus.
もう　エクソダスまで
１週間しかないんだ。
And... Gai wouldn't be acting
lazy right before an operation.
それに…　涯なら　作戦前の
こんなとき　ぼーっとしてない。
Funeral Parlor's leader, eh?
（谷尋）葬儀社のリーダーか。→
そのリーダーは　メンバーを脅して言うことを聞かせたりしてたか？
Did that leader threaten his
members into doing what he said?
どういうこと？
What's this about?
（谷尋）生徒たちに
不満が　たまってる。→
Resentment is building among the students.
You're going too far, Shu.
やり過ぎだ　集。
So what if they resent us? They all want
to be safe as soon as they can, right?
不満が何だ。
みんな　早く助かりたいんだろう？
祭のときだって…　規律がないからああいうことが起こったんだ。
When Hare...
That happened to her
because there was no discipline.
亞里沙さんを襲った犯人だって→
I know it was probably people
who resent us that attacked Arisa,
たぶん　僕らに
不満を持つやつらだろうけど。
だからって　もう引き返せない。
谷尋も　そう言ったろ？
but there's still no going back now.
You said so yourself, Yahiro.
（谷尋）確かに　そうだが。→
Of course, but we do still need ways
to make sure they don't feel oppressed.
抑圧を感じさせないための
工夫はいる。
（亞里沙）《だ…　誰か！！》
S-Someone help!
（いのり）《ハッ！》
《あ…　あぁ…》
いのり？
Inori?
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
Nothing, I'm fine.
ううん。　大丈夫。
（亞里沙）誰か…　助けて…。
Someone... help me...
≪（バイブレーターの音）
（亞里沙）あっ！
（バイブレーターの音）
Hello.
（亞里沙）はい。
Yes.
≪（亞里沙）はい。
生徒たちは　もう　爆発寸前です。
The student body is on the verge of exploding.
（亞里沙）ええ。　桜満君が
今は　力で　それを抑え込んで…。
Yes, Ouma's keeping them
in check with his power for now...
≪（鍵の開く音）
（難波）桜満会長の批判は→
Criticizing President Ouma isn't
allowed, even for a Rank S like you.
たとえ　ランクＳのあなたでも
許されませんよ！
Who were you talking to?
（難波）誰と話していたんです？
言いたくなければ　結構。
If you don't want to tell me, that's fine.
I can easily find out by
looking at your call history.
通話記録を見れば
すぐに分かることです。
（亞里沙）うっ…！
（亞里沙）分かったわ。
All right.
じゃあ　あなたが
引き出してくれる？
Will you draw it out, then?
あっ！
My... Void...
私のヴォイド。
（数藤）本当に　いいのかい？
難波君。
You sure about this, Nanba?
（難波）ああ。
もう　前金も　もらっちまったしな。
Yeah. I already got an advance payment, after all.
（数藤）ふーん。
Well, I guess this means the time is about ripe.
（数藤）まっ　そろそろ
潮時ってことですかねっと。
Here goes.
（生徒）おい。
どういうことだよ　これ。
Hey, what's this about?!
"Shu Ouma's hiding it, but if
your Void breaks, you'll die with it."
（生徒）
「オウマシュウは隠してるが→
"Shu Ouma's hiding it, but if your Void breaks...
ヴォイドが壊れると…」→
そいつも死ぬ！？
...you'll die with it"?!
So he's hidden that from us
to use our Voids?! Screw him!
（生徒）ふざけんなよ…。→
それを隠して　俺たちのヴォイドを使ってたっていうのか！？
He's gotta pay... He's gotta pay, doesn't he?!
（生徒）許せねえ…。
許せねえよな…。
Drop dead, Shu!
（生徒）死ね　集！
You go to hell!
地獄に落ちろ！！
（議長）日本政府が出してきた
報告書には→
Ninety-eight cover-ups and
fabrications have been unearthed
９８カ所の隠蔽　捏造が
確認された。
in the reports from the Japanese government.
（軍人）やはり　あの男
茎道に任せたのは間違いだった。
I knew it was a mistake to
entrust this to that man Keido.
We've been reaching out to
them for almost a decade now...
（官僚）われわれは　１０年近くもの間彼らに　手を差し伸べ続けた。→
Don't you think we've done enough?
もう　よいのでは　ありませんか？
You want to abandon them?
（明華総帥）見捨てるというのか？
（官僚）消滅する日本円は→
The U.N. would exchange the defunct
Japanese yen at a fixed rate.
国連が固定レートで
引き換えることになります。
（明華総帥）うむ。
それなら…。
Mmm, in that case...
（議長）各界の合意が
得られたところで→
Now that we have the accord of
representatives from your various fields,
計画の詳細を説明してもらおうか。
let's hear the details of your plan.
（谷尋）くだらない噂を流すのは
感心しませんね。
It's not very nice to spread idle rumors.
"Rumors"?
（亞里沙）噂って？
As in the rumor that if your Void breaks, you die.
（谷尋）ヴォイドが壊れたら→
その本人も死んでしまう
というやつですよ。
Are you sure that's not
the truth, rather than a rumor?
噂ではなく　事実でなくって？
It's a rumor. If it weren't, our whole
establishment would break down.
（谷尋）噂ですよ。　そうでなければ
今の体制は崩壊する。
（亞里沙）それで　今度は　あなたが
口封じに来たというわけ？
So you've come to silence me this time, then?
"This time"?
（谷尋）今度？
Anyone who defies your
establishment is punished.
あなたたちの体制に
歯向かうことをすれば→
制裁を受ける。
そういうことでしょ？
Isn't that what you came to say?
We would never order something like that.
（谷尋）そんなこと
指示するはずがない。
そう。　じゃあ
犯人を教えてあげるわ。
I see. Let me tell you who did it, then.
僕は　いつか　報いを
受けるんじゃないだろうか。
I... wonder if I'll pay the penalty someday.
Penalty?
報い？
人の心を踏みにじった　罪の…。
For the sin of trampling
all over people's hearts...
それなら　いつか　私も…。
That's one I'll pay, too.
どうして　そんなことを？
Why would you say that?
I'm probably the one who hurt Kuhouin.
供奉院さんのケガ
たぶん　私が…。
何を言ってるの？
What are you talking about?
I thought she was about to
make trouble for you, Shu,
私　供奉院さんが　集を
困らせようとしてるって思って→
それで　気持ちが
ざわざわってなって→
and it made me shudder inside... and I probably...
たぶん…。
私　自分が怖い…。
I'm afraid of myself.
化け物の私が…。
Because I'm a... monster...
It's okay.
大丈夫だよ。　安心して。
Don't worry.
この学校じゃ　僕が王様なんだ。
In this school, I'm king.
誰にも　君のこと
傷つけさせやしない。
I'll never let anyone hurt you.
≪（ドアの開く音）
（谷尋）集。　供奉院　亞里沙を
襲った犯人が分かったぞ。
Shu.
I found out who attacked Arisa Kuhouin.
ふうん。　誰なの？
Huh. Who was it?
Inori Yuzuriha. And I have eyewitness testimony.
（谷尋）楪いのり。
その時刻の目撃証言も取れた。
I see. So?
そう…。　だから？
（谷尋）楪に　こだわり過ぎだ　集。→
You're too hung up on Yuzuriha, Shu.
特別扱いを許せば
抑えが利かなくなるぞ。
If we allow special treatment,
we'll lose control of the students.
ルールを守らせる人間が
ルールを破るのは…。
If an enforcer of the rules breaks them...
Shut up!
うるさい！！
谷尋だって　僕に　ヴォイドによる
死のことを黙ってたじゃないか！
Weren't you the one who
kept Void death from me?!
隠し事は　お互いさまだろ！？
やめて　集。
You've kept as many secrets as she has!
Shu, stop!
Don't you get it? It was to keep everyone alive!
分からないのか？
全員が助かるためだ！
You're lying!
嘘だ！
Don't whitewash this.
奇麗事を言うな！
You think I'm an idiot,
so you're trying to use me!
僕をバカだと思って
利用しようとしてるんだろう！？
（谷尋）そうじゃない。→
That's not it! I figured something out after Jun:
俺は　潤の件で気付いた。→
人は　よく間違う。→
People make a lot of mistakes, and
correcting those mistakes requires power.
間違いを正すためには力がいる。→
お前と協力しなければ
いけないと思ったんだ！
That made me think I needed to work with you!
その手に乗ると思うのか？
You expect me to buy that?
どうせ　また　いずれ
僕を売り飛ばす気なんだろう！？
I know you're planning to
sell me out eventually, Sugar!
シュガー！！
あっ…！
Yes, I'm sure I do sound like I'm lying.
確かに
嘘にしか聞こえんだろうな。
これも
俺のしてきたことの結果か…。
I suppose these are the
consequences of my actions...
ここを出ていけ　谷尋。
Get out of here, Yahiro.
You never thought of us
as friends in the first place.
最初から　僕らに
友情なんて　なかった。
そうだろう？
Isn't that right?
（谷尋）ああ。　そうだったな。
Yes, that's right.
（難波）寒川は
ランクＦのテント送りになったよ。
Samukawa got sent to the Rank F tents.
自業自得ってやつだな。
Like they say, you reap
what you sow. And here's this.
それと　これ。→
Just what you asked for:
the date and time of the Exodus,
お望みどおり　エクソダスの日時や生徒たちのヴォイド情報まで。
and the info on the students' Voids, too.
What do you intend to use it for?
（難波）そんなもの
何に使うつもりなんだ？
（亞里沙）クーデター。
（難波）えっ？
A coup d'état.
裸の王子さまを
引きずり下ろすの。
I'm going to force the emperor
and his new clothes out of power.
Move out starting with the groups who are ready.
（鶫）「準備ができた班より
移動を開始してください」→
「目的地の東京タワーまでは
約４ｋｍ」→
Our destination, Tokyo Tower,
is about four kilometers away.
「１ｋｍごとに
休憩　点呼を取る予定です」
We'll take a break after each
kilometer and do a roll call.
（鶫）詳しくは
班長の指示に従ってください。
Follow your squad leader's
orders about the details.
The mood today is off, somehow.
（綾瀬）何か　嫌なムードね。
（生徒）合図は供奉院さんからだ。
（生徒）分かってる。
Kuhouin will give the signal.
We know.
（生徒）Ｂ組には回ってるの？
（生徒）タイミング　間違えるなよ。
Has Team B gotten the news?
Don't get the timing wrong.
And we're sure the fix is
in with the Secret Service?
（生徒）親衛隊は
大丈夫なんだよな？
Kanon?
（谷尋）花音？
難波。
はい。
Nanba.
Yes?
みんなは　僕のことを
どう思っているのかな？
What does everyone think of me?
皆を解放するリーダーとして
感謝を捧げていますよ。
They're grateful to you,
the leader who will free them all.
そうか…。
I see...
♪♪～
（ローワン）「学生たちが
移動を開始しました」
The students are on the move.
Just like the plan leaked to us.
（茎道）
リークされた計画どおりだな。→
目的地は東京タワーか。
（ローワン）「はい」→
Are they headed for Tokyo Tower?
Yes, Sir.
「このままなら　桜田通りで
学生たちと接触します」
Unless something changes, we'll make
contact with them on Sakurada Street.
（茎道）そうか…。
I see...
And so we're about to see
the advent of the true king.
これで　間もなく
真の王が降臨する。
（ユウ）天王洲で　最大値の
ゲノムレゾナンスを計測しました。
I've measured the maximum value
of the genomic resonance in Tennozu.
The index variation is 281.
（ユウ）
指数のバリエーションは２８１通り。
Honestly, you've done so well collecting them...
（ユウ）まったく…。
よく集めてくれましたよねぇ。
もう一度　計画を説明する。
I'll go over the plan one more time.
ゴースト部隊のコントロール装置は
この東京タワーにある。
The machine controlling
the Ghost unit is here in Tokyo Tower.
僕がヴォイドを使って　タワーの支柱に高圧電流を流し込む。
I'll use Voids to send a high-voltage
current through its struts.
その電流が支柱を伝わり
ショートさせれば→
If I short the machine that way,
I should be able to render the Ghosts powerless.
ゴースト部隊を
無力化できるはずだ。
君たちには
そのための道をつくってもらう。
You will create a path to get me there.
Go to your designated posts and
hold back the enemy's defense Insects.
指定された配置に従って
敵の防衛用インセクトを抑えるんだ。
成功すれば　晴れて　僕らは
ウォールから出ることができる。
If we succeed, we'll officially
be able to get outside the wall.
頑張ろう。
Let's work hard.
They're here!
≪（生徒）来たぞ！
（一同の　どよめき）
ひるむな！
Don't be daunted! We have Voids on our side!
僕らには　ヴォイドがある！
（亞里沙）進みましょう　桜満君。→
Let's go forward, Ouma.
Not for anyone else, but for our own futures!
誰のためでもない
私たちの未来のために！
Begin the operation!
作戦開始！
♪♪～
There are twenty Auto-Insects,
just like we expected.
オートインセクトの数は２０！
予想どおりだよ。
（生徒たち）うわぁ…！
（生徒）くっそぉ！
Dammit!
（生徒）うわぁぁ！
（律）会長！　道が開けました。
Mr. President, the path is open.
《僕は　彼らを
体のいい　おとりにしたのか？》
Did I use them as glorified decoys?
Shu...
集。
Inori...
いのり。　大丈夫だよ。
心配しないで。
It's okay. Don't be worried.
《今は反省してる場合じゃない》
This isn't the time for soul-searching.
♪♪～
（和美）あっ！
（生徒）あっ！　和美！！
Kazumi!
会長　どこへ！？
Sir, where are you going?
♪♪～
行くぞ。
Let's go!
♪♪～
《やる。　やってやる！》
I'll do this. I'm doing this!
I don't...
《僕は　もう…》
《誰も失いたくないんだ！》
...want to lose anyone else!
♪♪～
うおぉぉ！！
うおぉぉぉ！！
♪♪～
（亞里沙）さあ　皆さん！
Come, everyone.
今のうちに
レッドラインを越えましょう。
Let's cross the red line while we can.
急いで！
Quickly!
It's over, Inori.
終わったよ　いのり。
うん。
Mm-hmm.
Come on, let's follow them.
さあ　僕らも行こう。
どうした？　お前たち。
What's with you three?
- What do you think you're doing?!
- Shu!
どういうつもりだ！？
集！
Inori, you stay back.
（アルゴ）いのり。　お前は行くな。
You can't go out there, Aya!
（鶫）綾姉は出ちゃ駄目！
（綾瀬）鶫！？
Tsugumi?
（難波）ご苦労さまでした。
会長さん。→
Great work, Mr. President.
あなたの役目は終わりました。→
Your work is done now.
We'll go on alone from here.
ここからは
われわれだけで行きますから。
There you have it.
（亞里沙）そういうことよ。
亞里沙さん！
これは　あなたが…！？
Arisa! Did you do this?!
答える必要あるのかしら。
Do I really need to answer that?
（颯太）フン！
えっ？
I'm not doing anything wrong... I'm not...
（颯太）俺は悪くない。
悪くない…。
颯太？
Souta?
（生徒）よくも
俺たちを道具にしたな。
- How dare you use us as tools!
- Who said you could peek inside my heart?!
（生徒）人の心をのぞき見して！
（生徒）ひきょう者！
- Coward!
- Parasite!
（生徒）寄生虫が！
（生徒）死ね！　うざいんだよ！
Drop dead! We're sick of you!
Shu!
集！
Hey!
おい！
いのり。
Inori!
いのり！
≪（悲鳴）
♪♪～
Gai?!
涯！？
来てくれたのね…。
You came for us.
♪♪～
（涯）久しぶりだな　集。
Long time no see, Shu.
えっ？
ああ…　ああ…　ああぁ…！
ああぁぁ…。
あっ…！　あぁ…　あぁぁ。
Shu...
集…。
うっ…　うあぁぁ！！
う…　腕が…！！
My arm!
僕の王の力が…！！
My king's power!
We'll now take a vote on
United Nations Resolution 17,
（議長）それでは
国連動議　第１７号。→
日本消滅計画について
決を採ります。
the project to terminate Japan.
Approved by majority vote.
（議長）賛成多数により　承認。→
We'll now proceed to drop the RM warheads.
これより
ＲＭ弾頭の射出に移行する。
ううっ…。
（涯）王だと？→
"King"?
忘れたのか？
お前は横取りしただけ。
Have you forgotten? You were just a usurper.
（涯）最初から　王は俺だった。
The king has always been me.
♪♪～
What am I supposed to care about,
left behind alone in a world like that?
I spent so many days,
accumulated so many feelings
And you were by my side the whole time,
A fixture of my life, and when you left,
I discovered their weight for the first time
If I'd gripped your hand tight
that day and not let go...
In the end, I was only living
in my own self-satisfied world
"Now it's like I'm a liar
for saying I did it all for you"
Even those murmured words don't reach you
Run, run to you
Watch, I'll fall as often,
get lost as often as it takes
Wait for me, because I'm on my way
No matter what difficulties are waiting there